Guide to the William Manchester Papers, 1934 - 2004
William Manchester Papers1934 - 2004
Series IX: Media contains audio and micro cassettes, videocassettes, floppy disks, and all associated materials. Manchester's research interviews and recorded versions of his books are found here. There are no media materials related to The Death of a President, except for a Dictabelt apparently containing dictation Manchester made in the office of his agent in September, 1966. Materials have not been reviewed and identification is taken from the labeling found on the item.
Series X: Realia
Three-dimensional objects such as mementoes, awards, wallets and wallet cards, keys, military paraphernalia, hats, and a variety of other objects are briefly described.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Manchester, William, 1922-2004.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-1994.; Krupp family.; MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1960.; Rockefeller family.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davidson), 1839-1937.; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davidson), 1874-1960.; Churchill, Winston, 1874-1965.; World War, 1939-1945--Pacific Ocean.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Personal narratives, American.; United States. Marine Corps--Biography.; United States--History--1933-45.; United States--History--1945-; Soldiers--United States--Biography.; Authors, American--20th century--Biography.; Middle Ages.; Renaissance.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Faculty.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968.; American Education Publications.; Audiotapes.; Drafts.; Floppy disks.; Galley proofs.; Notebooks.; Photographs.; Realia.; Scrapbooks.; Videotapes.
Bibliography
Books written by William Manchester:
American Caesar. Boston: Little Brown, 1978.
Arms of Krupp, The. Boston: Little, Brown, 1968.
Beard the Lion. New York: M.S. Mill, 1958.
City of Anger, The. New York: Ballantine Books, 1953.
Controversy. Boston: Little, Brown, 1976.
Death of a President, The. New York: Harper & Row, 1967.
Disturber of the Peace. New York: Harper, 1951.
Glory and the Dream, The. Boston: Little, Brown, 1974
Goodbye, Darkness. Boston: Little, Brown, 1980.
In Our Time. New York: American Federation of Arts in association with Norton, 1989.
Last Lion, The: William Spencer Churchill: Visions of Glory. Boston: Little, Brown, 1983
Last Lion, The: William Spencer Churchill: Alone. Boston: Little, Brown, 1988.
Long Gainer, The. Boston: Little, Brown, 1961.
One Brief Shining Moment. Boston: Little, Brown, 1984.
Portrait of a President. Boston: Little, Brown, 1962.
Rockefeller Family Portrait, A. Boston: Little, Brown, 1959.
Shadow of the Monsoon. New York: Doubleday, 1956.
World Lit Only By Fire, A. Boston: Little, Brown, 1992.
Selected articles and other writings of William Manchester (articles written for The Daily Oklahoman and The Sunpapers not included):
Act of Conscience, An. Good Housekeeping, Nov. 1968.
All the News-and Then Some. The Reader's Digest, Dec. 1959.
American Caesar. The Reader's Digest, July 1979.
Anatomy of a Novelist. The Wesleyan University Alumnus, Aug. 1960.
Anatomy of a Novelist. Our Times, Nov. 9, 1960.
Another Bloody Country Gone West. MHQ: The Quarterly Journal of Military History 9 (1997, Winter).
At Home with Churchill. The Illustrated London News, May, 1987.
Berkshire Hills, The. Holiday, Aug. 1961.
Birthday Bouquets for H. L. Mencken. The Nation, Sept. 12, 1952.
Byrd Machine, The. Harper's, Nov. 1952.
Captain of the Gate. Leadership South Africa 7 (1988).
Case of Luella Mundel, The. Harper's, May 1952.
Censors are Cooking Mother Goose, The. The Democratic Digest, June 1954.
Churchill at Home. Leadership South Africa 6 (1987).
Day in the Life of Winston Churchill, A. The Reader's Digest, Nov., 1987.
Death of a President, The-Part 1. Look, Jan. 24, 1967.
Death of a President, The-Part 2. Look, Feb. 7, 1967.
Death of a President, The-Part 3. Look, Feb. 21, 1967.
Death of a President, The-Part 4. Look, March 7, 1967.
Department of Defense, The-Tenth in a Series. Holiday, May 1963.
Department of the Treasury, The-Second of a Series. Holiday, Feb. 1962.
Enemy of the People, An?. The Nation, Aug. 9, 1952.
First World War, The. Holiday, Nov. 1962.
Founding Grandfather, The. The New York Times Magazine, Oct. 6, 1974.
Great Bank Holiday, The. Holiday, Feb. 1960.
Great Vivisection Dog Fight, The. Look, June 6, 1950.
H. L. Mencken at Seventy-Five. Saturday Review, Sept. 10, 1955.
H. L. Mencken in Person. Horizon, Sept. 1980.
House of Krupp, The, Part 1. Holiday, Oct. 1964.
House of Krupp, The, Part 2. Holiday, Nov. 1964.
House of Krupp, The, Part 3. Holiday, Dec. 1964.
House of Krupp, The, Part 4. Holiday, Jan. 1965.
House of Krupp, The, Part 5. Holiday, Feb. 1965.
In Defense of Snobs. Esquire, Dec. 1962.
John F. Kennedy: A Man Alone. Our Times, Sept. 19, 1962.
John F. Kennedy: Portrait of a President-Part One. Holiday, Apr. 1962.
John F. Kennedy: Portrait of a President-Part Two. Holiday, May 1962.
John F. Kennedy: Portrait of a President-Part Three. Holiday, June 1962.
Kennedy Family. Encyclopaedia Britannica, 15th ed., 1974.
Krupp. Look, Aug. 6, 1968.
Life Along the Connecticut. Holiday, June 1963.
Life and Times of a Slum Landlord, The. The Reporter, Nov. 15, 1956.
Lion Caged, The. American Heritage, Feb.-March, 1987.
Louisville Cashes in on Culture. Harper's, Aug. 1955.
Louisville Cashes in on Culture. The Reader's Digest, Oct. 1955.
Louisville, Belle of Kentucky. Holiday, Jun 1957.
Manchester on Leadership. Modern Maturity, Oct.-Nov., 1988.
Maryland's Historic Capital. Holiday, June 1958.
Mencken and the Mercury. Harper's, Aug. 1950.
Mencken and the Twenties. Harper's, July 1950.
Money, Bears, and Bulls-A Look at Wall Street. Holiday, March 1964.
Monster on the Loose. 21, Oct. 1951.
Murder Tour of New England. Holiday, May 1961.
Nelson Rockefeller's Moral Heritage. Harper's, May 1959.
Okinawa: The Bloodiest Battle of All. In The Dolphin Reader, compiled by Douglas Hunt. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1990.
Okinawa: The Bloodiest Battle of All. In Subject and Strategy, Paul A. Escholtz and Alfred F. Rosa. New York: St. Martin's Press, 1990.
Our Hospitals are Sick. Baltimore Sunpapers, 1951.
Our Teenage Drug Addicts. The Freeman, June 4, 1951.
Our War in the Pacific. Holiday, Nov. 1960.
Paris Embassy, The. Holiday, March 1969.
Private Life of H. L. Mencken, The. Gardens, Houses, and People, Nov. 1950.
Record Run. he Saturday Evening Post, Apr. 13, 1957 [short story].
Reflections on Egalitarianism. National Review, March 22, 1985.
Rock Bottom in America. New York, Aug. 5, 1974.
Small Loans Play a Vital Role in Our Economy. The Democratic Digest, July, 1954.
Spanish-American War, The. Holiday, Sept. 1961 30:3.
Structured Exposition. Connecticut English Journal, Spring 1977 8:2.
Then. The New York Times Magazine, Nov. 4, 1973.
There Are Limits to Charity. Trustee, Apr. 1972.
There Is No Conspiracy. Trustee, July 1952.
Thirty-Six per Cent Interest-And 'No Que$tions Asked.' The Reporter, Apr. 13, 1954.
Three Misspent Lives. Esquire, Oct. 1968.
Three Yellow Tickets. Decade of Short Stories, 1947.
Times, The: The World's Greatest Newspaper. Holiday, Oct. 1959.
Treasury, The: Inside the Nation's Vaults. Sky, Sept. 1976.
Tribal American, The. Holiday, July 1962.
Undaunted by Odds. MHW: The Quarterly Journal of Military History Spring 10 (1998).
United States Marines, The. Holiday, Nov. 1957.
Walking With Destiny: An Extract from The Last Lion. Leadership South Africa 7 (1988).
Walter Reuther-Part I. Holiday, Nov. 1959.
Walter Reuther-Part II. Holiday, Dec. 1959.
William Manchester's Own Story. Look, Apr. 4, 1967.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: Writings, 1943-1995
  - Books
    - American Caesar
      - Correspondence
        - 1975 Oct-Dec (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - 1976 Jan-Dec (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - 1977 Mar-Dec (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - 1978 Jan-Mar (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - 1978 Apr-Jun (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - 1978 Jul (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - 1978 Aug-Dec (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - 1979 Feb-Jul (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - 1979 Dec - 1980 Jan and undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Conkovich, Stephen, 1979 Nov (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Research materials
        - Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Carmichael: The Ninety Days (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - Carmichael: The Ninety Days (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - Clippings, 1939-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Department of Defense Directory, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - Gunther: The Riddle of MacArthur (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
        - Higgins: Korea and the Fall of MacArthur (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
        - Lang: MacArthur Day in Chicago (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
        - Liberation of the Philippines (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - Maps (Box 3, Folder 2)
        - NYT Index, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
        - NYT Index, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
        - NYT Index, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - NYT Index, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - NYT Index, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - NYT Index, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
        - NYT Index, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
        - NYT Index, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
        - NYT Index, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - NYT Index, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - NYT Index, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - NYT Index, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - NYT Index, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - NYT Index, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - Research materials (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - Rovere: The General and the President (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
      - Documents
        - Index of documents (Box 3, Folder 20)
        - 1-30 (Box 3, Folder 21)
        - 31-60 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - 61-90 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - 91-120 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - 121-150 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - 151-180 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - 181-210 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - 211-240 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - 241-270 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        - 271-300 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - 301-330 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - 331-362 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - 363-386 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Research notes
        - Index (Box 5, Folder 3)
        - James: The Years of MacArthur, Vol. I (Box 5, Folder 4)
        - Eyre - Borton (Box 5, Folder 5)
        - Baldwin - Brereton (Box 5, Folder 6)
        - pp. 1-81 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        - pp. 82-184 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        - pp. 185-298 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        - pp. 299-389 (Box 5, Folder 10)
        - pp. 390-521 (Box 5, Folder 11)
        - pp. 522-619 (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - pp. 620-718 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        - pp. 718-824 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - pp. 825-921 (Box 6, Folder 4)
        - pp. 922-1031 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - pp. 1032-1199 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - pp. 1200-1231 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        - pp. 1232-1336 (Box 6, Folder 8)
        - Interviews (Box 6, Folder 9)
        - Research notes, 1976 Jan and undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - Notebook, 1976 Apr (Box 6, Folder 11)
        - Docs 1-84 (Box 6, Folder 12)
        - Docs 85-177A (Box 6, Folder 13)
        - Docs 178-248 (Box 6, Folder 14)
        - Docs 249-328 (Box 6, Folder 15)
        - Docs 1-60 [duplicates] (Box 6, Folder 16)
        - Charts (Box 6, Folder 17)
        - Codes and indexes, ca. 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - General (Box 7, Folder 2)
        - MacArthur miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - Outlines, ca. 1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - Clumps (Box 356-361)
      - Original draft
        - Front matter (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - Preamble (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - Prologue (Box 7, Folder 7)
        - Reveille, 1880-1917 (Box 7, Folder 8)
        - First Call, 1917-1918 (Box 7, Folder 9)
        - Order Arms, 1919-1935 (Box 7, Folder 10)
        - To the Colors, 1935-1941 (Box 7, Folder 11)
        - Retreat, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 12)
        - The Green War, 1942-1944 (Box 7, Folder 13)
        - At High Port, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Last Post, 1945-1950 (Box 8, Folder 2)
        - Sunset Gun, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 3)
        - Recall, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 4)
        - Taps, 1951-1964 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Working notes (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous notes from scrapbox (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Fair copy
        - Prologue: The First General MacArthur (Box 8, Folder 8)
        - One: Reveille (Box 8, Folder 9)
        - Two: First Call (Box 8, Folder 10)
        - Three: Order Arms (Box 8, Folder 11)
        - Four: To the Colors (Box 8, Folder 12)
        - Five: Retreat (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - Six: The Green War (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Seven: At High Port (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Eight: Last Post (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Nine: Sunset Gun (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Ten: Recall (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - Eleven: Taps (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Acknowledgments/bibliography (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Bibliography (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Bibliography (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Chapter notes (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Chapter notes (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Chapter notes [alternate version] (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Copy editing, 1978 Feb-Apr (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Endpapers [2 copies] (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Preamble: Reveille [2 copies] (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Revisions, 1978 Mar and undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Specimen pages, 1978 Mar (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Setting copy, 1978 Apr (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Setting copy, 1978 Apr (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
      - Setting copy, 1978 Apr (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
      - Author's file set (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Author's file set (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
      - Post galley material, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Last Caesar file, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Australian serialization, 1978 Dec - 1979 Jan (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Press kit (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Photo booklets [two copies] (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Promotion and reviews, 1978 Jul-Oct (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Remarks at dedication of MacArthur Square, 1978 Jul-Dec (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Miniseries reviews, 1985 Mar (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - Oversize (Box 433)
    - The Arms of Krupp
      - Correspondence
        - 1951 Jul-1963 Mar (Box 14, Folder 1)
        - 1963 Apr-Aug (Box 14, Folder 2)
        - 1963 Sep-1966 Sep (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - 1967 Jan-Jun (Box 14, Folder 4)
        - 1967 Jul-Dec (Box 14, Folder 5)
        - 1968 Jan-Jun (Box 14, Folder 6)
        - 1968 Jul-Sep (Box 14, Folder 7)
        - 1968 Oct-Dec (Box 14, Folder 8)
        - 1969 Jan-1970 Jul and undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
        - Empty envelopes, bulk 1963 (Box 14, Folder 10)
        - Kaufman, 1969 Jan-1971 Feb (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Interviewees, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - Die firma Krupp, 1962-63, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Research materials
        - Research materials (Box 15, Folder 1-8)
        - Research materials (Box 16, Folder 1-6)
        - Research materials (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Alfred Krupp Briefe (Box 17, Folder 2-5)
        - Ferencz Brief (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
        - German passports (Box 17, Folder 8)
        - Maps (Box 17, Folder 9)
        - Krupp clippings, 1959 Mar-1972 Jan (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Documents
        - Index of Docs / Codes (Box 18, Folder 2)
        - 1-20 (Box 18, Folder 3)
        - 21-40 (Box 18, Folder 4)
        - 41-60 (Box 18, Folder 5)
        - 61-80 (Box 18, Folder 6)
        - 81-82 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Krupp notes
        - A: Letters (Box 18, Folder 8)
        - B, Pam, C, P, Docs (Box 18, Folder 9)
        - Europe: May (Box 18, Folder 10)
        - Europe: June (Box 18, Folder 11)
        - From Jim Bell (Box 18, Folder 12)
        - Menne (Box 18, Folder 13)
        - Muhlen (Box 18, Folder 14)
        - N.D. (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - P, B, Pam. (Box 19, Folder 2)
        - Pounds (Box 19, Folder 3)
        - U.S.A. Interviews (Box 19, Folder 4)
        - Von Klass (Box 19, Folder 5)
        - Young (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Research notes
        - Research notebook - 0 (Box 19, Folder 7)
        - Research notebook - I (Box 19, Folder 8)
        - Research notebook - II (Box 19, Folder 9)
        - Research notebook - III-IV (Box 19, Folder 10)
        - Research notebook - IV (Box 19, Folder 11)
        - Research notes (Box 19, Folder 12-13)
        - Research notes (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
        - Indexes and outlining (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - Outlines of material which has been written (Box 20, Folder 4-11)
        - Translated passages (Box 20, Folder 12)
        - Clumps (Box 362-364)
      - Holiday, 1964-65
        - First draft: installment I (Box 20, Folder 13)
        - First draft: installment II (Box 20, Folder 14)
        - First draft: installment III (Box 20, Folder 15)
        - First draft: installment IV (Box 20, Folder 16)
        - First draft: installment V (Box 20, Folder 17)
        - Draft: installment I (Box 20, Folder 18)
        - Draft: installment II (Box 20, Folder 19)
        - Draft: installment III (Box 20, Folder 20)
        - Draft: installment IV (Box 20, Folder 21)
        - Draft: installment V (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Original draft
        - Front matter (Box 20, Folder 23)
        - Notes (Box 20, Folder 24)
        - Prologue (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - Chapter I (Box 21, Folder 2)
        - Chapter II (Box 21, Folder 3)
        - Chapter III (Box 21, Folder 4)
        - Chapter IV (Box 21, Folder 5)
        - Chapter V (Box 21, Folder 6)
        - Chapter VI (Box 21, Folder 7)
        - Chapter VII (Box 21, Folder 8)
        - Chapter VIII (Box 21, Folder 9)
        - Chapter IX (Box 21, Folder 10)
        - Chapter X (Box 21, Folder 11)
        - Chapter XI (Box 21, Folder 12)
        - Chapter XII (Box 21, Folder 13)
        - Chapter XIII (Box 21, Folder 14)
        - Chapter XIV (Box 21, Folder 15)
        - Chapter XV (Box 21, Folder 16)
        - Chapter XVI (Box 21, Folder 17)
        - Chapter XVII (Box 21, Folder 18)
        - Chapter XVIII (Box 22, Folder 1)
        - Chapter XIX (Box 22, Folder 2)
        - Chapter XX (Box 22, Folder 3)
        - Chapter XXI (Box 22, Folder 4)
        - Chapter XXII (Box 22, Folder 5)
        - Chapter XXIII (Box 22, Folder 6)
        - Chapter XXIV (Box 22, Folder 7)
        - Chapter XXV (Box 22, Folder 8)
        - Chapter XXVI (Box 22, Folder 9)
        - Chapter XXVII (Box 22, Folder 10)
        - Chapter XXVIII (Box 22, Folder 11)
        - Chapter XXIX (Box 22, Folder 12)
        - Chapter XXX (Box 22, Folder 13)
        - Chapter XXXI (Box 22, Folder 14)
        - Chapter XXXII (Box 22, Folder 15)
        - Chapter XXXIII (Box 23, Folder 1)
        - Epilogue (Box 23, Folder 2)
        - Appendices (Box 23, Folder 3)
        - Sources (Box 23, Folder 4)
        - Extra memeos for CAS visit 12/21 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Fair copy, 1968 Feb
        - Copy 1 (Box 23, Folder 6-10)
        - Copy 1 (Box 24, Folder 1-6)
        - Copy 2 (Box 25, Folder 1-6)
        - Copy 2 (Box 26, Folder 1-5)
        - Annotated (Box 26, Folder 6-7)
        - Annotated (Box 27, Folder 1-7)
        - Annotated (Box 28, Folder 1-4)
      - Addendum to bibliography, 1968 Apr (Box 28, Folder 5-7)
      - Front matter (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Epilogue (see epoligue file in cabinet) (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Appendices (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - Questions (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Chronology (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Inserts (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Sources (Box 28, Folder 14-15)
      - Revisions, Krupp (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Revisions, live file (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Revisions - dormant file (and last Krupp material) (Box 29, Folder 3-4)
      - Corrections, 1968-69 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Front and back matter, 1968 Apr-May (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
      - Setting copy (Box 29, Folder 8-10)
      - Setting copy (Box 30, Folder 1-6)
      - Setting copy (Box 31, Folder 1-5)
      - Proof - vol I (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Proof - vol II (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Proof - vol III (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Proof - vol I (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Proof - vol II (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Proof - vol III (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Galleys (Box 365)
      - Book News: Little, Brown & Co., [1968?] (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Look, 1968
        - Article based on Krupp book, 1968 Jan (Box 32, Folder 7)
        - Article based on Krupp book, 1968 Apr-Jun (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Photocopy of book with edits (Box 33, Folder 2-4)
      - Photocopy of portions of book (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Materials returned by agent (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Screenplay treatment: Notes and correspondence, 1969 Mar-May (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Screenplay treatment: First draft, 1969 Mar (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Screenplay treatment, 1969 May (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
      - Oversize (Box 434)
    - Beard the Lion, 1958
      - Research and correspondence (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
      - Notes and outlines (Box 34, Folder 3-5)
      - Notebook (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Notebook (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Clippings (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Draft (Box 34, Folder 9-20)
    - City of Anger, 1953
      - Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 1-5)
      - Review letters from prominent individuals (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Plot summary (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Clippings (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Research notes (Box 35, Folder 9-12)
      - Background materials (Box 35, Folder 13-14)
      - Draft (Box 35, Folder 15-26)
      - Draft (Box 36, Folder 1-14)
      - Fair copy (Box 36, Folder 15-18)
      - Proofs (Box 366)
      - Galleys (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - Dust jacket (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - Reviews (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - 1967 ed. (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - 1985 ed. (Box 37, Folder 3-7)
    - Controversy and Other Essays in Journalism
      - Correspondence, 1969, 1975-76 (Box 37, Folder 8-10)
      - Drafts and notes (Box 37, Folder 11-13)
      - Controversy
        - Research material (Box 37, Folder 14-21)
        - Research material (Box 38, Folder 1-5)
        - William Manchester's Own Story (Box 38, Folder 6)
        - 151st annual report, Harper & Row, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 7)
        - Manchester Unexpurgated, Commentary, 1967 Jul (Box 38, Folder 8)
        - Restricted research material (Box 470)
        - Clumps (Box 367)
        - First draft (Box 38, Folder 9-12)
        - Fair copy (Box 38, Folder 13-15)
      - The Spanish-American War (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - The First World War (Box 38, Folder 17)
      - The Island War (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - Corps d'Elite (Box 38, Folder 19-20)
      - The Department of Defense (Box 38, Folder 21-22)
      - The Man Who Couldn't Speak Japanese (Box 38, Folder 23-27)
      - The Great Bank Holiday (Box 38, Folder 28)
      - Wall Street (Box 38, Folder 29)
      - The Treasury Department (Box 38, Folder 30-31)
      - Loan Sharks (Box 38, Folder 32)
      - Slum Landlords (Box 38, Folder 33)
      - The Tribal American (Box 38, Folder 34)
      - Murder Tour of New England (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Life Along the Connecticut (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - The Berkshire Hills (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - The New York Times (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - An Act of Conscience (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - A Slight Case of McCarthyism (Box 39, Folder 6-9)
      - Our Embassy in Paris (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Cairo After Farouk (Box 39, Folder 11-16)
      - Adlai in Defeat (Box 39, Folder 17-20)
      - Walter Reuther (Box 39, Folder 21)
      - The Founding Grandfather (Box 39, Folder 22)
      - My Old Man (Box 39, Folder 23-24)
      - In Defense of Snobs (Box 39, Folder 25)
      - Draft
        - Front matter (Box 39, Folder 26)
        - Controversy (Box 39, Folder 27)
        - The Spanish-American War (Box 39, Folder 28)
        - The Great War (Box 39, Folder 29)
        - The Island War (Box 39, Folder 30)